# MICHELLE KAPLAN

# Software Engineer | Denver, CO

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer who loves to build and create! Experience working with cross-functional and global teams, utilizing my excellent communication skills to communicate goals and objectives. Empathetic to the user and understand the user journey and implementation of human centered design.

#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

• Phone: 303-519-0805

• Email: michellekaplan.dev@gmail.com

GitHub: michellekaplan7LinkedIn: kaplanmichelle

#### **SKILLS**

**Object Oriented Programming:** JavaScript (ES5, ES6), React, React Hooks, Redux, HTML, CSS/Sass, iQuery

**Test Driven Development:** Mocha, Chai, Jest, React Testing Library

**Tools:** Webpack, Travis Cl, Postman, Netlify, Heroku, Fetch, Axios, NPM

**UI/UX:** Wireframing (Adobe XD, Miro, InVision), Accessibility

#### **EDUCATION**

Turing School of Software & Design | Denver, CO

Jan. 2020 to Aug. 2020 Front End Engineering

## Colorado State University | Fort Collins, CO

Aug. 2013 to Dec. 2016

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

- University Honors Student, Cum Laude
- Concentration: Marketing, Strategic Marketing Certificate

• GPA: 3.877

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Nanno | Denver, CO - Remote

Software Engineer | Sept. 2020 to Dec. 2020

- Modernized a Rails monolithic app into a progressive web app
- Built a React/Redux front-end and integrated it to a new back-end
- Designed and implemented testing strategy for front-end components
- Collaborated with other team members with an agile approach
- Lead and participated in technical design meetings, pair programming sessions and code reviews
- Wrote understandable, testable code with an eye towards maintainability and scalability

# Cochlear Americas | Centennial, CO

Services and Marketing Specialist | July 2018 to Oct. 2019

- Developed paid Facebook campaigns that resulted in over \$80,000 of revenue
- Created and implemented a newsletter strategy, aiming to increase engagement and open rates for 55,000 recipients
- Managed the production of recipient testimonial videos, including editing, approval, publishing, and marketing
- Managed the scholarship program, awarding 8 people \$2,000/year, up to 4 years

Services and Marketing Coordinator | Sept. 2017 to July 2018

- Managed social media, newsletters and blog calendars, including writing Facebook/Twitter posts through Spreadfast
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to manage the production of both print and digital assets

#### **PROJECTS**

Additional work at: <a href="https://alumni.turing.io/alumni/michelle-kaplan">https://alumni.turing.io/alumni/michelle-kaplan</a>

### Find My Market - React Native / Expo

GitHub / YouTube Demo | August 2020

- Mobile (iOS) geolocation app built to help find farmers markets within a 50 mile radius from the users location
- Full-stack team project using React Native, React Native Maps, React Hooks, Expo, Jest, React Testing Library

#### Wizard Harry - React / Router

GitHub / Deployed Application | June 2020

- Website for Harry Potter fans to get advice from Hermione, be sorted by school, and view/save/sort spells
- Solo project using JavaScript, React, Router, Jest, React Testing Library, fetch API, PropTypes, local storage